A Guide to the William Hewitt Phillips Papers, 1918-2008
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series I. 2004 Donation
  - Landing, 1967-1976, n.d. (Box-folder 16-12)
  - Large Space Structures, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 17-1)
  - Light Planes, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 17-2)
  - LLTV [Lunar Landing Training Vehicle] Accident Review, 1968-1969, n.d. (Box-folder 17-3)
  - Lunar Landing Vehicle, Apollo - Approach Stability and Control Review, 1969 (Box-folder 17-4)
  - Lunar Module - Landing Approach Review, 1964 (Box-folder 17-5)
  - Lunar Orbiter, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 17-6)
  - Lunar Orbiter, Meeting on Orbit Determination Techniques for, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 17-7)
  - Lunar Orbiter - Transfer Orbit, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 17-8)
  - Man-Powered Airplane, 1977 (Box-folder 17-9)
  - Mars Airplane, 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 17-10)
  - Mars Airplane (VU Graphs), 1978 (Box-folder 17-11)
  - Mimic Program, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 17-12)
  - Model Reference Systems, n.d. (Box-folder 17-13)
  - Moments Acting on a Satellite, [1958?] (Box-folder 17-14)
  - Moon,1964 (Box-folder 17-15)
  - Nonlinear Systems, 1974 (Box-folder 17-16)
  - NTF (Natural Transonic Facility), 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 17-17)
  - Oblique Wing, 1971 (Box-folder 18-1)
  - Observer Sensitivity, Reports on, 1971-1972, n.d. (Box-folder 18-2)
  - Oscillating Airfoils, 1950-1977 (Box-folder 18-3)
  - Parameter Identification, 1973-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 18-4)
  - Propellers for High-Alt Airplane, 1957-1978 (Box-folder 18-5)
  - Propulsive Efficiency, 1968 (Box-folder 18-6)
  - Prostheses, 1973 (Box-folder 18-7)
  - Radiation, 1977 (Box-folder 18-8)
  - Radio-Controlled Models, n.d. (Box-folder 18-9)
  - Redundancy, Analytical Reliability, 1956-1975 (Box-folder 18-10)
  - Relativity, 1963, n.d. (Box-folder 18-11)
  - Rendezvous, 1959-1962, n.d. (Box-folder 18-12)
  - Rendezvous (Recent), 1963, n.d. (Box-folder 18-13)
  - Rendezvous, Infra-red Sensors for Rendezvous, 1965, n.d. (Box-folder 18-14)
  - Research Environment (Memos), 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 18-15)
  - Ride Comfort, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 18-16)
  - Rocket Theory, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 18-17)
  - Rotating Cylinder Flaps, 1963-1971, n.d. (Box-folder 18-18)
  - Rotating Satellites, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 18-19)
  - Shuttle (Memos, Notes, Etc.), 1974-1981, n.d. (Box-folder 19-1)
  - [Shuttle] Aerodynamics, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 19-2)
  - [Shuttle] Case Proposals on Backup Flight Control System, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 19-3)
  - Shuttle Control System, n.d. (Box-folder 19-4)
  - Shuttle Control System - Effect on Positive Elevator Feedback, 1978-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 19-5)
  - Shuttle Control System - Reports from Ken Adler, 1973-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 19-6)
  - Shuttle Engine Controls, 1978 (Box-folder 19-7)
  - Shuttle - Entry and Landing, 1973-1980 (Box-folder 19-8)
  - Shuttle Headquarters for ALT, 1977, n.d. (Box-folder 19-9)
  - [Shuttle] Hydraulic Subsystem, 1973 (Box-folder 19-10)
  - [Shuttle] Inertial System, 1971-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 19-11)
  - [Shuttle] Langley Contributions, 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 19-12)
  - [Shuttle] Priority Rate Limiting, n.d. (Box-folder 19-13)
  - Shuttle, Recommendations for, 1973-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 19-14)
  - Shuttle, Role of Man in, 1973-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 19-15)
  - Shuttle Software Problems, 1973 (Box-folder 19-16)
  - Shuttle Study Request, 1973 (Box-folder 19-17)
  - Shuttle Time Lags and Pilot-Induced Oscillations (PIO), 1973-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 19-18)
  - Signal Flow Diagrams, 1964, n.d. (Box-folder 20-1)
  - Simulated Design, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20-2)
  - Solar Power Station, 1977 (Box-folder 20-3)
  - Solar Sail, 1977, n.d. (Box-folder 20-4)
  - Solar Sail, 1977 (Box-folder 20-5)
  - Spanwise Averaging, 1976-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 20-6)
  - Spheres, Flow on, 1995, n.d. (Box-folder 20-7)
  - SPIFR (Single Pilot Instrument Flight Rules), n.d. (Box-folder 20-8)
  - Spin Bibliography, n.d. (Box-folder 20-9)
  - Spin Research, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 20-10)
  - Stability, Lateral, 1978 (Box-folder 20-11)
  - Stability, Longitudinal, 1954 (Box-folder 20-12)
  - Stability Longitudinal, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 20-13)
  - Stability, Spiral (Hewes Article), 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 20-14)
  - Stalling, 1975 (Box-folder 20-15)
  - Stalls, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 20-16)
  - Steam Cars, 1971 (Box-folder 20-17)
  - STOL Reports, 1992 (Box-folder 20-18)
  - Tail-Mounted Turbofan Engine, 1969 (Box-folder 20-19)
  - Tethered Body, 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 20-20)
  - Tethered Helicopter, 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 20-21)
  - Thrusts Due to Gusts (folder 1 of 2), 1974-1977, n.d. (Box-folder 20-22)
  - Thrusts Due to Gusts (folder 2 of 2), 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 21-1)
  - Unsteady Lift Reports, 1970-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 21-2)
  - Unsteady Lift Reports, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 21-3)
  - Use of Tail Cone in ALT Tests, 1976 (Box-folder 21-4)
  - [Vertical Flight, First] - Conference at MSC on Question of Man in First Vertical Flight (Box-folder 21-5)
  - Vertical Flight - Manned vs. Unmanned; Cheatham, David C., 1973 (Box-folder 21-6)
  - Viking Notes, Memos, Etc., 1973-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 21-7)
  - Viking Stab. Analysis, 1974-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 21-8)
  - VTOL Proposed Design, 1969 (Box-folder 21-9)
  - Washout Design, 1973-1975, n.d. (Box-folder 21-10)
  - Wind Shear (Abzug), n.d. (Box-folder 21-11)
  - Windmill Boat, 1971 (Box-folder 21-12)
  - Airfoil Design Method by Teodorsen - Article by Waldo Oehman, 1978 (Box-folder 21-13)
  - Airfoil Programs (PROFILX), 1989, n.d. (Box-folder 21-14)
  - Airfoils: Boundary Layer Controlled Thick Suction Airfoils, 1994 (Box-folder 21-15)
  - Airfoils for High Lift - Liebeck, n.d. (Box-folder 21-16)
  - Airfoils: Thick Suction Airfoils - Sidney Goldstein, 1948 (Box-folder 21-17)
  - Airfoils: Three Papers by Phillips, 1985, n.d. (Box-folder 21-18)
  - Airfoils: Velocity Ahead of an Airfoil: Program by R. T. Jones, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 22-1)
  - Airfoils with Thick Trailing Edge - Douglas Co., n.d. (Box-folder 22-2)
  - Altitude Response - Initial Studies, 1979 (Box-folder 22-3)
  - Apollo, NASA Contributions, 1974-1994 (Box-folder 22-4)
  - Attitude Control - Dr. Rublein Contract, 1981 (Box-folder 22-5)
  - Bibliographies on Handling Qualities, 1981-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 22-6)
  - Boundary Layer Studies, 1977-1987, n.d. (Box-folder 22-7)
  - Canards - High Lift Configuration, 1971-1984 (Box-folder 22-8)
  - Circulation Control, 1987-1989 (Box-folder 22-9)
  - Complimentary Filter - Report by John Garren et. al., 1977 (Box-folder 22-10)
  - Contributions by Langley Engineers - Listed by Phillips, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 22-11)
  - Crescent Wing Studies, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 22-12)
  - Departure Maneuvers (Stalls), 1980 (Box-folder 22-13)
  - Dryden Lecture by Phillips, 1989 (Box-folder 22-14)
  - Education - Senior Projects, n.d. (Box-folder 22-15)
  - Flight Control Review Group, Shuttle, 1974-1979, n.d. (Box-folder 22-16)
  - Fuzzy Logic, 1992, n.d. (Box-folder 22-17)
  - Hang Glider - Correspondence and Reports, 1975-1982, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 23-1)
  - Hang Glider - Data and Trajectory Calculations, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 23-2)
  - Joined Wings - Publicized by Wolkovitch, 1986 (Box-folder 23-3)
  - Larrabee, E. Eugene - Copies of Talks, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 23-4)
  - Mars Airplane, 1978, n.d. (Box-folder 23-5)
  - Paper Airplane - World's Largest, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 23-6)
  - Papers on Airfoil Drag, 1937-1992 (Box-folder 23-7)
  - Photos of Langley's Aerodrome and Some Data, 1992, n.d. (Box-folder 23-8)
  - Pilot-Induced Oscillations, 1992 (Box-folder 23-9)
  - Plot of Energy Efficiency in Climb - Used in Study of Solar Aircraft, 1979 (Box-folder 23-10)
  - Pressure Drag of Airfoil, 1988-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 23-11)
  - Project Teal Rain, DARPA Project on Solar-Powered Aircraft, 1979-1980, n.d. (Box-folder 24-1)
  - Propeller Design for Very High Altitude Airplane, 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 24-2)
  - Pterodactyl Replica Designed by Paul McCready and Henry Jex, 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 24-3)
  - Scaling, 1992, n.d. (Box-folder 24-4)
  - Scaling, Paper for Journal of Aircraft, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 24-5)
  - Scaling, References - Compilation of Non-Dimensional Numbers, [1904?]-1992 (Box-folder 24-6)
  - Seventy-fifth Anniversary Book - Comments, 1990 (Box-folder 24-7)
  - Shuttle - Entry Concerns and Oscillations of Elevons, 1980, n.d. (Box-folder 24-8)
  - Shuttle Navigation System - Raymond Montgomery, 1979, n.d. (Box-folder 24-9)
  - Shuttle Pilot-Induced Oscillation Problem (PIO), n.d. (Box-folder 24-10)
  - Solar-Powered Aircraft - von Flotow, Daedelus, 1988, n.d. (Box-folder 24-11)
  - Solar-Powered and Microwave-Powered Aircraft, References, 1953-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 24-12)
  - Stagnation Point Flow, 1957 (Box-folder 24-13)
  - Submarine - Longitudinal Response to Elevator Control, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 24-14)
  - Turbulence Response - Ribner and Filotas, 1969-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 24-15)
  - Underwater Vehicles, 1981, n.d. (Box-folder 25-1)
  - Vought F8U-I - Compilation of Memos, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 25-2)
  - Wedge Trailing Edge - Flexible, 1991-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 25-3)
  - Wind Tunnel Built for Virginia Air and Space Center, 1941-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 25-4)
  - Wing Leveler Fluidic, 1978 (Box-folder 25-5)
  - Winglets, 1962-1978, n.d. (Box-folder 25-6)
  - Yachts, 1972-1984, n.d. (Box-folder 25-7)
  - Measurements of the Longitudinal Stability and Control Characteristics of the Vought-Sikorsky XF4U-1 Airplane Memorandum Report for Bureau of Aeronautics, Aug 30 1941 (Box-folder 25-8)
  - Effect of Spring and Gravity Moments in the Control System on the Longitudinal Stability of the Brewster XsBA-1 Airplane, Apr 1942, [2 copies] (Box-folder 25-9)
  - Measurements of the Flying Qualities of a Hawker Hurricane Airplane, Apr 1942, [2 copies] (Box-folder 25-10)
  - A Flight Investigation of Short-Period Longitudinal Oscillations of an Airplane with Free Elevator, May 1942 (Box-folder 25-11)
  - Control-Surface Instability of High-Speed Airplanes, Jun 1942 (Box-folder 25-12)
  - Comparison of Aileron Control Characteristics as Determined in Flight Tests of P-36, P-40, Spitfire, and Hurricane Pursuit Airplanes, Aug 1942 (Box-folder 25-13)
  - Measurements of the Flying Qualities of a Submarine Spitfire Va Airplane, Sep 1942, [2 copies] (Box-folder 25-14)
  - Stalling Characteristics of the Submarine Spitfire Va Airplane, Sep 1942, [2 copies] (Box-folder 25-15)
  - A Flight Investigation of the Stability of a Towed Body, Oct 1942, [3 copies] (Box-folder 25-16)
  - Flight Test of Various Tail Modifications on the Brewster XSBA-1 Airplane I-Measurements of Flying Qualities with the Original Tail Surfaces, Jul 1943 (Box-folder 25-17)
  - Flight Tests of Various Tail Modifications on the Brewster XSBA-1 Airplane II - Measurements of Flying Qualities with Tail Configuration Number Two, Dec 1943 (Box-folder 26-1)
  - Measurements of the Flying Qualities of a Curtis SB2C1-Airplane, Mar 1944 (Box-folder 26-2)
  - Stability of a Body Stabilized by Fins and Suspended from an Airplane, Apr 1944 (Box-folder 26-3)
  - Application of Spring Tabs to Elevator Controls, Oct 1944 (Box-folder 26-4)
  - Effect of Lateral Shift of Center of Gravity on Rudder Deflection Required for Trim, Nov 1944 (Box-folder 26-5)
  - Application of Spring Tabs to Elevator Controls, 1944 (Box-folder 26-6)
  - The Use of Geared Spring Tabs for Elevator Control, Feb 1945 (Box-folder 26-7)
  - An Investigation of Additional Requirements for Stability Elevator Control Characteristics, Jun 1946 (Box-folder 26-8)
  - Effect of Steady Rolling on Longitudinal and Directional Stability, Jun 1948 (Box-folder 26-9)
  - Appreciation and Prediction of Flying Qualities - Technical Report 927, 1948-1949, [2 items: NACA Technical Note 1670 (Aug 1948) and NACA Report 927 (1949)] (Box-folder 26-10)
  - Theoretical Analysis of Oscillations of a Towed Cable, Jan 1949 (Box-folder 26-11)
  - Low-Speed Tests of a Model Simulating the Phenomenon of Control-Surface Buzz, Aug 1950 (Box-folder 26-12)
  - Ability of Pilots to Control Simulated Short-Period Yawing Oscillations, Nov 1950 (Box-folder 26-13)
  - Theoretical Study of Some Methods For Increasing The Smoothness of Flight through Rough Air, Jul 1951 (Box-folder 26-14)
  - Theoretical Analysis of Some Simple Types of Acceleration Restrictors, Dec 1951 (Box-folder 26-15)
  - Effects on Longitudinal Stability and Control Characteristics of a Boeing B-29 Airplane of Variations in Stick-Force and Control-Rate Characteristics Obtained through Use of a Booster in the Elevator-Control System, 1952 (Box-folder 26-16)
  - Flight Investigation of Mechanical Feel Device in an Irreversible Elevator Control System of a Large Airplane, 1952 (Box-folder 26-17)
  - Graphical Solution of Some Automatic-Control Problems Involving Saturation, Aug 1953 (Box-folder 26-18)
  - Review and Investigation of Unsatisfactory Control Characteristics Involving Instability of Pilot-Airplane Combination and Methods for Predicting These Difficulties from Ground Tests, Aug 1953 (Box-folder 26-19)
  - Theoretical Investigation of Some Discontinuous Yaw Dampers, Apr 1954 (Box-folder 26-20)
  - A Method For Measuring The Product of Inertia and the Inclination of the Principal Longitudinal Axis of Inertia of an Airplane, Apr 1954 (Box-folder 26-21)
  - Investigation of Effect of Reduction of Valve Friction in a Power Control System by Use of a Vibrator, Jul 1955 (Box-folder 26-22)
  - Analysis of Automatic Control to Prevent Rolling Divergence, Apr 1956 (Box-folder 27-1)
  - Investigation by the Transonic-Bump Method of a 35° Sweptback Semispan Model Equipped with a Flap Operated By A Series of Servovanes Located Ahead of and Geared to the Flap, Apr 1956 (Box-folder 27-2)
  - Theoretical Calculation of the Power Spectra of the Rolling and Yawing Moments on a Wing in Random Turbulence, Dec 1956 (Box-folder 27-3)
  - Loads Implications of Gust-Alleviation System, Jun 1957 (Box-folder 27-4)
  - Flight Investigation of the Effectiveness of an Automatic Aileron Trim Control Device for Personal Airplanes, 1957 (Box-folder 27-5)
    Scope and Contents note
    [also includes "Simulator Studies of Several Lateral Stability Augmentation Concepts for Light Aircraft" by H. Douglas Garner (Langly Working Paper 999, Oct 6 1971)]
  - Subsonic Flight Investigation of Methods to Improve the Damping of Lateral Oscillations by Means of a Viscous Damper in the Rudder System in Conjunction with Adjusted Hinge-moment Parameters, Jan 1958 (Box-folder 27-6)
  - A Method for the Calculation of the Lateral Response of Airplane to Random Turbulence, Feb 1958, [2 copies] (Box-folder 27-7)
  - Analysis of a Cable in a Satellite Orbit, Jun 15 1959 (Box-folder 27-8)
  - The Lateral Response of Airplanes To Random Atmospheric Turbulence, 1960 (Box-folder 27-9)
  - Research on Blunt-Faced Entry Configurations at Angles of Attack Between 60° and 90°, 1960 (Box-folder 27-10)
  - A Longitudinal Control Feel System for In-Flight Research on Response Feel, Jan 1961 (Box-folder 27-11)
  - Analysis of Effects of Interceptor Roll Performance and Maneuverability on Success of Collision-Course Attacks, Aug 1961 (Box-folder 27-12)
  - Propulsive Efficiency of Tail-Mounted Turbofan Engines, Dec 1968 (Box-folder 27-13)
  - Effects of Spanwise Variation of Gust Velocity on Alleviation System Designed for Uniform Gust Velocity Across Span, Jan 1971 (Box-folder 27-14)
  - Effect on a Glider of Its Own Trailing Vortices in Circling Flight, Jan 1972 (Box-folder 27-15)
  - Analysis of Effect of Asymmetric Loading on Sailplane Performance in Circling Flight, Oct 1972 (Box-folder 27-16)
  - Effect of the Method of Obtaining Lateral Trim on the Drag of a Glider in a Steady Turn, 1972 (Box-folder 27-17)
  - Gyroscopic Moments on a Glider in Turning Flight, 1972 (Box-folder 27-18)
  - Study of the Control System to Alleviate Aircraft Response to Horizontal and Vertical Gusts, Dec 1973 (Box-folder 27-19)
  - Analysis of Experimental Studies of the Control of Hang Gliders, 1974 (Box-folder 27-20)
  - Recovering from a Vertical Dive, 1975 (Box-folder 27-21)
  - Propulsive Effects Due to Flight Through Turbulence, 1975 (Box-folder 27-22)
  - Investigation of Longitudinal Control System for a Small Hydrofoil Boat, 1976 (Box-folder 27-23)
  - Stability and Control of Hang Gliders, 1976 (Box-folder 27-24)
  - Ground Distance Covered During Airborne Horizontal Deceleration of an Airplane, Apr 1978 (Box-folder 27-25)
  - Simulation Study of the Oscillations Longitudinal Motion of an Airplane at the Stall, Aug 1978 (Box-folder 27-26)
  - Altitude Response of Several Airplanes During Landing Approach, Nov 1979 (Box-folder 27-27)
  - Some Design Considerations for Solar-Powered Aircraft, Jun 1980 (Box-folder 27-28)
  - Analytical Study of a Fireplace Heat Exchanger, Feb 1981 (Box-folder 27-29)
  - Flight Research on F8U-1 Airplanes, Sep 1981 (Box-folder 28-1)
  - Studies of Friction Drag and Pressure Drag of Airfoils Using the Eppler Program, Oct 1988, [see also Oversize] (Box-folder 28-2)
  - Dryden Lecture - Flying Qualities from Early Airplanes to the Space Shuttle, Jul 1989 (Box-folder 28-3)
  - Determination of the Pressure Drag of Airfoils by Integration of Surface Pressures, Oct 1990, [2 copies] (Box-folder 28-4)
  - Recollections of Langley in the Forties - Talk by W.H. Phillips, Jun 1992 (Box-folder 28-5)
  - Effects of Model Scale on Flight Characteristics and Design Parameters, Mar-Apr 1994 (Box-folder 28-6)
  - Accuracy of Frequency Response - Fourier Series, 1951-1952, n.d. (Box-folder 28-7)
  - Aircraft Stability and Control - Miscellaneous Notes, 1945-1950, n.d. (Box-folder 28-8)
  - Effect of Roll Collision Course Attacks - Book I, 1957, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 28-9)
  - Effect of Roll Collision Course Attacks - Book II, 1957, n.d. (Box-folder 28-10)
  - (Volume VII) Experimental Methods in High-Speed Aerodynamics Section N Piloted Aircraft Testing by Bailey, Zalovcik, Phillips and Huston, n.d. (Box-folder 29-1)
  - (Article on) Gust Alleviation Presented as Part of a Series of Technical Talks at Rensselaer (Box-folder 29-2)
  - Gyro Lecture - Phillips (Box-folder 29-3)
  - Lunar Landing Facility, 1961-1967, n.d., [3 folders] (Box-folder 29-4)
  - Moments on Satellites; Pearson Lecture Series; Density Determination; Control in Free Space, 1958-1959, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 29-5)
  - Phase Plane Methods, 1952-1953, n.d. (Box-folder 30-1)
  - Space Stabilization - Bibliography (Box-folder 30-2)
  - Space Stabilization Talk for Interns, n.d. (Box-folder 30-3)
  - Stabilization Work, Material for Talk on, 1959, n.d. (Box-folder 30-4)
  - Stable Platform Lecture W.H.P., 1959 (Box-folder 30-5)
  - Theory of Stability of Aircraft and Other Physical Systems, n.d. (Box-folder 30-6)
  - VU-Graphs Dynamic Stability Lecture (folder 1 of 2), 1963-1976, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 30-7)
  - Phillips Notes for Lecture Preparations, 1950, n.d. (Box-folder 30-8)
  - Diedrich - Introduction to Matrix Analysis, n.d. (Box-folder 30-9)
  - [Diedrich] Matrix Notes, n.d. (Box-folder 30-10)
  - Diedrich, Matrix Notes on Course by, 1950, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 30-11)
  - Dr. Eade Course - Calculus of Variation (Box-folder 31-1)
  - Dr. Kalman Lectures; Dr. Dreyfers Lectures (Box-folder 31-2)
  - Dr. Katzoff Course - Modern Physics (Box-folder 31-3)
  - Rempfer Lectures - Dr. Nashed (Box-folder 31-4)
  - Envelope of Typical Printouts from the Eppler Program, [3 items] (Oversize 1)
- Series II. 2010 Donation
  - Subseries I. Writings and Lectures, 1936-2000
    - Advantages of the Right-Right Pattern, n.d. (Box-folder 32-1)
    - Analysis of a Cable in a Satellite Orbit, 1959 (Box-folder 32-2)
    - Analysis of Effect of Assymetric Loading on Sailplane Performance in Circling Flight, 1972 (Box-folder 32-3)
    - Analysis of Means to Increase the Smoothness of Flight in Rough Air, n.d. (Box-folder 32-4)
    - Analysis of the Article "The Outlook for the Flying Machine" by Professor Simon Newcomb (October 1903), 1982 (Box-folder 32-5)
    - Analytical Study Using a Human Pilot Model of Effect of Adverse Lift Due to Elevon Deflection on Control Characteristics, 1991, n.d. (Box-folder 32-6)
    - Applications fo Aerodynamic Theory to Stability, n.d. (Box-folder 32-7)
    - Appreciation and Predictions of Flying Qualities, 1945 (Box-folder 32-8)
    - Comparison of the Scope of Ship and Airplane Handling Qualities [glass plates], n.d. (Box-folder 32-9)
    - Design Considerations for One-bladed Propellers, n.d. (Box-folder 32-10)
    - Design of Electrically-powered Models to Reach Maximum Altitude, n.d. (Box-folder 32-11)
    - Designing a Rubber-powered Model to Carry a Payload, 1991 (Box-folder 32-12)
    - Development of Transonic Test Facilities, 1996, n.d. (Box-folder 32-13)
    - Dune Soaring at Kitty Hawk, ca. 1955-1994 (Box-folder 32-14)
    - Dynamic Stability and Control Class Lectures, n.d. (Box-folder 32-15-33-1)
    - Effect of Expansion and Contraction of the Surfaces on Shape of a Wedge-shaped Trailing Edge, 1992 (Box-folder 33-2)
    - Effect of Pressure Gradients on the Boundary Layer Along a Flat Plate (MIT undergraduate thesis), 1939, [original and photocopy] [2 folders] (Box-folder 33-3)
    - Effect of the Variation of L/D with Lift Coefficient on the Ease of Making Power-Off Landings, n.d. (Box-folder 33-4)
    - Effects of Model Scale on Flight Characteristics, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 33-5)
    - Endurance of Indoor Models at Low Ceilings, 1936-1994, n.d. (Box-folder 33-6)
    - Experiments on Methods of Measuring the Lift-Drag Ratio of Airfoils, n.d. (Box-folder 33-7)
    - Flight Control Research [videocassette], 1986 (Box-folder 33-8)
    - Flight Investigation of the Effect of Friction on Power Boost Systems, n.d. (Box-folder 33-9)
    - Flight Tests of an Airplane with Sweptback Wings, n.d. (Box-folder 33-10)
    - Fluid Control Systems, 1966 (Box-folder 33-11)
    - Flying and Handling Qualities of Airplanes, n.d. (Box-folder 33-12)
    - Flying Qualities from Early Airplanes to the Space Shuttle, 1987-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 33-13)
    - Flying Qualities from Early Airplanes to the Space Shuttle, 1988-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 34-1)
    - Flying Qualities of Airplanes at Transonic Speeds, n.d. (Box-folder 34-2)
    - Free Flight articles, 1977-1993 (Box-folder 34-3)
    - The Friction Drag and Pressure Drag of Airfoils, 1984, n.d. (Box-folder 34-4)
    - Gust Alleviation (Rensselaer Lecture), 1970, n.d. (Box-folder 34-5)
    - Gust Alleviation as a Subject for Research, 1975-ca. 2000 (Box-folder 34-6)
    - Hidden Treasures in Old NACA Reports, 2000, n.d. (Box-folder 34-7)
    - High-speed Flight Stability and Control Problems, 1954 (Box-folder 34-8)
    - High-speed Stability and Control Problems, 1953 (Box-folder 34-9)
    - How Does an Airfoil Produce Lift?, [1978?]-1983 (Box-folder 34-10)
    - How to Defeat Drag, n.d. (Box-folder 34-11)
    - Hydrodynamic Coefficients of an Elongated Body Rapidly Approaching a Free Surface, 1976 (Box-folder 34-12)
    - Investigation of Canard Surfaces to Improve Handling Characteristics of the Shuttle Orbiter, 1988 (Box-folder 34-13)
    - Investigation of Longitudinal Control System for a Small Hydrofoil Boat, 1976 (Box-folder 34-14)
    - Is Wing Covering Necessary?, n.d. (Box-folder 34-15)
    - Jump-start for Tow-line Gliders, 1989 (Box-folder 34-16)
    - Langley Research Center Simulation Facilities for Manned Space Missions, [1963] (Box-folder 34-17)
    - Load Implications of Gust Alleviation Systems, n.d. (Box-folder 34-18)
    - Manual for Preparation of NFFS Symposium Volume, [1975?] (Box-folder 34-19)
    - Model aircraft articles, 1939-1991, n.d., [2 folders] (Box-folder 35-1)
    - Model Airplanes and Science (talk for Armstrong School), n.d. (Box-folder 35-2)
    - Moments Acting on a Satellite, 1959 (Box-folder 35-3)